<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Jackson Noel - Jackson Noel</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 22:11:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/author/jackson/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>test</title><description>&lt;p&gt;test&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/test/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">28306d65-6799-4767-ac6b-3274a4f56311</guid><dc:creator>Jackson Noel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 23:00:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Writing</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I've been a citizen of the internet for almost as long as I can remember, and generally like to consider myself an early adopter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not once did I hop on the blogging train. No blogger, tumblr, wordpress: none of that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at this ripe age of 29, I've finally done it. I'm committing myself to writing, and this is my first ever (personal) blog post. So as my first post, I thought it'd only be fitting to reflect on why. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why I haven't done this yet, what's changed that makes me want to commit to writing, and what I hope to gain from doing so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="whyhaveinotdonethisyet"&gt;Why have I not done this yet?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've never considered myself a particularly strong writer. Don't get me wrong, I've been proud of my writing at times. But it has never really come naturally to me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not one of those students who could crank out a beautifully crafted paper in 90 minutes. It always took me longer to get to the quality level with which I was satisfied. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that's reason number one: Writing is hard (for me). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason number two is different. &lt;em&gt;What do I have to say that people would actually want to read?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, I thought I had nothing unique to contribute. My areas of passion are already crowded with thought leaders. And I already love reading their work. So I couldn't imagine how I could meaningfully contribute to any audience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="sowhathaschanged"&gt;So what has changed?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I met one of the scrappiest, most clever people I know. We were having coffee and towards the end of our conversation he asked me if I blogged. I said no and sort of shrugged it off. But then he replied, "you really should. I do and everything I'm passionate about is up there."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those words really stuck with me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This person, of course, was &lt;a href="http://jonathan-kim.com/"&gt;Jonathan Kim&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, he was working on a startup by himself called Appcues. A couple of months later, I was fortunate enough to join him as his co-founder (I'll save that story for another post). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Jonathan and I started to work together, I took over our &lt;a href="http://appcues.com/academy/"&gt;User Onboarding Academy&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of long form lessons on the best practices of user onboarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my hesitations about writing, I was eager about working on the academy. After all, the goal was to use content to draw more visitors to the site, turn a small percentage of those visitors into customers, and help us grow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So writing = &lt;strong&gt;$&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the academy hasn't only helped the company grow. It helped me grow. And it gave me a renewed appreciation for writing that goes beyond any extrinsic motivations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id="writinghasallowedmetodevelopexpertise"&gt;Writing has allowed me to develop expertise&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no shortage of reading material on the internet. So in order for our academy to actually get visitors, we'd have to create thoughtful, compelling and original content. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there were two problems with that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I thought I sucked at writing  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn't know that much about onboarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, most of my career had been in finance and I only had one year of experience working at a software startup. While I had done some work on user onboarding before, I was by no means an expert. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in order to write quality academy lessons, I first had to learn. I did extensive research on user experience, behavioral psychology, data analytics, you name it. For many of the posts, this meant spending 20-30 hours researching (reading, talking to experts, etc.) before writing a single word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id="writinghashelpedmehelpothers"&gt;Writing has helped me help others&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do I have to say that people would actually want to read?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After writing consistently for Appcues for six months, I have every reason to chalk up this old hesitation of mine as delusional. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that time, the User Onboarding Academy has gained tens of thousands of readers and 2,000+ email subscribers. But more importantly than the stats, are the folks who reach out to ask a question or just to say thanks. They always make me smile :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="sowhatsthisblogallabout"&gt;So what's this blog all about?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing process has forced me to become a better thinker. A better learner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by doing so, it's allowed me to help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these came as a pleasant surprise to me. So I'm starting this blog is to build off of that momentum. Hopefully it will continue to help me grow personally and professionally. And hopefully others will find it worthy of a read. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I learn more and as my experience with Appcues evolves, this is where I'll come to share. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/writing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f2050018-d9ec-4a82-941e-c3f3ba2588a5</guid><dc:creator>Jackson Noel</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 22:02:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>